Van den Haag, Ernest; Papers apap135
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications, 1949-2000; 2; 7.49 cubic ft.
  - Numbered, 1950-2000; 2.1; 6.17 cubic ft.
    - 238. Review of "Human Social Development" by Dorothy Blisten, Social Forces, 1974 September (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 58)
    - 239. Reply to Alfonso J. Damico on Amnesty, Dissent, 1974 Summer (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 59)
    - 240. Testimony on Emergency School Aid Act of 1970 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 60)
    - 242. "The Breakdown of Authority", Reader's Digest Almanac, 1970 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 61)
    - 243. "The Nixon Haters", New York Times, 1973 December 17 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 62)
    - 245. "A Free Society's Need", In "This is the F.B.I.", edited by Richard O. Wright, Americans for Effective Law Enforcement, 1973 November (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 63)
    - 246. Letter to the Editor on Alexander Bickel's Watergate Article, Commentary, 1974 April (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 64)
    - 247. "A Perversion of the Constitution", Reply to Eugene McCarthy on Nixon, Skeptic, 1974 May-1974 June (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 65)
    - 248. "Professor Against Porn", Interview, Screw Magazine, 1974 April 01 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 66)
    - 249. "Reflections on the Issue of Gay Rights", In "Taking Sides", edited by George Mckenna, and National Review, 1974 July 19 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 67)
    - 250. "Affirmative Action for Balance", Prospect, Princeton Alumni, 1974 June 03 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 68)
    - 251. "Black Cop-Out", National Review, 1974 August 30 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 69)
    - 252. "Finally, He was Right to Resign", (Nixon), National Review, 1974 August 30 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 70)
    - 253. "Free Speech and Censorship", Newsletter on Intellectual Freedom, 1974 September (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 71)
    - 253a. "The Perimeters of Free Expression", The Alternative, 1975 December (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 72)
    - 254. Review of "Deterrence: The Legal Threat in Crime Control" by Franklin Zimring, Contemporary Sociology, 1974 September (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 73)
    - 255. Political Threat to the Market Economy, Address delivered to the Mont Pelerin Society, Brussels, 1974 September 12 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 74)
    - 256. "What Pardons are For", Letter to the Editor on Ford's Pardon of Nixon, New York Times, 1974 November 03 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 75)
    - 257. "Intricacies of Boredom", Letter to the Editor on Estelle Ramey's "Bordom", Harpers, 1975 January (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 76)
    - 258. "Should We Subsidize Popular Culture?" Sunday New York Times, 1975 February 09 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 77)
    - 259. "How Much Justice", Modern Age, 1975 Winter (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 78)
    - 260. "Broyard's Bouquet", Review of Anatole Broyard's "Aroused by Books", National Review, 1975 February 26 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 79)
    - 261. "A Fable", Occasional Review, 1974 Fall (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 80)
    - 262. "Handguns V. Knives", Letter to the Editor on Franklin Zimring's Pierce on Handguns, Wall Street Journal, 1975 January 13 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 81)
    - 263. "Id/Yid", Letter to the Editor on M.J. Sobran's Review of "Lenny and Bruce", National Review, 1975 January 31 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 82)
    - 264. "Keeping Amnesty on Course", Letter to the Editor on George Nash's Amnesty International Article, National Review, 1975 January 17 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 83)
    - 265. Review of "Campustown in the Throes of the Counterculture", by Mark Graubard, National Review, 1975 January 31 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 84)
    - 266. Letter to the Editor on Hadley Arkes' "The Problem of Kenneth Clark", Commentary, 1975 March (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 85)
    - 267. "Justice and the Market", Intercollegiate Review, 1975 Winter (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 86)
    - 267a. Reply to Tibor Machan's letter "Justice and the Market", Intercollegiate Review, 1976 Winter-Spring (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 87)
    - 268a. "Monopoly", Letter to the Editor on Shirley MacLain's article on China, Sunday New York Times, 1975 April 20 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 88)
    - 269. Answer to Question "Is Homosexuality Biologically Unnatural?" Homosexual Counseling Journal, 1975 January (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 89)
    - 270. "The Social Function of Religion", The Religious Imperative Conference, Rockford College, Rockford, Ill, 1974 November 15-1974 November 17 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 90)
    - 271. "Two Myths of Gun Control", True, 1975 July (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 91)
    - 272. "The Libertarian Argument", Review of "Anarchy State and Utopia" by Robert Nozxick, National Review, 1975 July 04 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 92)
    - 273. "Betraying the Psychoanalytic Revolution", Review of "Social Amnesia" by Russell Jacoby, Psychology Today, 1975 September (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 93)
    - 274. "Coalition in Italy?" National Review, November 7, 1975, and related letters to the Editor, National Review, November 19, 1975 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 94)
    - 275. "Overestimation of Sexuality", Medical Aspects of Human Sexuality, 1975 October (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 95)
    - 276. "Cheerfulness is Always Breaking In", Review of "Execution Eve" by William F. Buckley, Jr., National Review, 1975 October 24 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 96)
    - Review of "Sociobiology: The New Synthesis" by Edward O. Wilson, Harvard, 1975, and National Review, 1975 October 10 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 97)
    - 278. "Straight Talk for Homosexuals", Review of "The Homosexual Matrix" by C.A. Tripp, Harpers, 1976 January (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 98)
    - 279. Reviews of "Punishing Criminals" by E.v.d. Haag, Basic Books, 1975 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 99)
    - 279b. Serialization of "Punishing Criminals" by E.v.d. Haag, Basic Books, 1975, In New York Post, 1976 February 06 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 100)
    - 280. "Crime Deterrence and Offender Career", Report prepared for the Office of Economic Opportunity under grant by the Hudson Institute, 1975 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 101)
    - 281. "No Excuse for Crime", In The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Sciences, 1976 January (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 102)
    - 282. Letter to the Editor on Edgar Z. Friedenberg's review of "Executions in America" by W.J. Bowers, Society, 1976 January-1976 February (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 103)
    - 283. "Bring Back the Death Penalty?: Pro and Con", Interview in U.S. News and World Report, 1976 April 19 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 104)
    - 284. "Wealth and Power", Letter to the Editor on "Tax Wealth. Not Income" by Lester Thurow, New York Times, Sunday, 1976 May 23 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 105)
    - 285. "Notes on the Ideology and Psychology of Planning", In Politics of Planning" edited by A. Lawrence Chickering, Institute for Contemporary Studies, 1976 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 106)
    - 286. "Consensual Government", Review of "The Morality of Consent" by Alexander Bickel, Vanderbilt Law Review, Vol. 29:521, 1976 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 107)
    - 287. Letter to the Editor on "The Death Penalty Decisions" by Michael Meltsner, Wall Street Journal, 1976 April 30 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 108)
    - 288. "For Those Who Murder Why Not Death?" The Baltimore Sun, Perspective, 1976 July 11 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 109)
    - 289. "Why Criminals are Running Wild and What Can Be Done to Curb Them", American Views, 1976 June 07 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 110)
    - 290. Letter to the Editor on "The Warrior Intellectuals" by Francis Fitzgerald, Harpers, 1976 July (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - 291. "What To Do About TV Violence", The Alternative, 1976 August-1976 September (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - 292. "What Is A Liberal? Who Is A Conservative?" Commentary, 1977 March 18 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - 293. "Economics Is Not Enough", The Public Interest, 1976 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - 294. "Critics of Corrections Speak Out", Interview, Corrections, 1976 March; 1976 June (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - 295. "Reverse Discrimination", The Review of Education, 1976 September-1976 October (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - 295a. "Reverse Discrimination", National Review, 1977 April 29 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - 296. "What Is A Civil Libertarian To Do When Pornography Becomes So Bold?" Interview with Gay Talese, Sunday New York Times, Arts and Leisure Section, 1976 November 21 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - 297. "The Death Penalty: A Deterrent", The Wall Street Journal, 1976 December (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - 298. "The Peddling of Pornography Is Not an Inalienable Right", Baltimore Sun, Perspective, 1976 December 26 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - 299. Review of "Knowledge and Politics" by R.M. Unger, National Review, 1976 December 10 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - 300. Review of "Jean Paul Sartre" by Arthur Danto, National Review, 1977 February 04 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - 301. "Haggis and the Wealth of Nations", National Review, 1977 March 04 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - 302. "No" (Re: Is The Republican Party Dead?), National Review, 1977 March 18 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
    - 303. "Crime, Punishment and Deterrence", Society, 1977 March-1977 April; 1977 September-1977 October (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
    - 304. "Preventing Crime with Punishment", The Alternative, 1977 May (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
    - 305. Reply to Jack P. Gibbs' review of "Punishing Criminals", The Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1976 December (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
    - 306. Letters to the Editor between Jerome H. Skolnick, E.v.d. Haag, and Sidney Hook, Contemporary Sociology, 1975-1979 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
    - 307. "Equity or Chiliasm?" Review of "Sharing the World's Resources" by Oscar Shacter, National Review, 1977 May 27 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
    - 309. "A Note on the Sentencing of Criminals", Policy Review, 1977 Summer (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
    - 310. "The Effectiveness of Punishment", Moral Choices in Contemporary Society - Courses by Newspaper, 1977 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
    - 311. "Criminal Affluence", Review of "The Growth of Crime" by Sir Leon Radzinovicz, National Review, 1977 November 25 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
    - 312. "In Defense of the Death Penalty: A Legal, Practical, Moral Analysis", Criminal law Bulletin, 1978 January-1978 February (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
    - 313. "Should the Activities of the Communist Party Be Restricted By Law?" Transcript of Radio Debate, WBAI-FM, New York, 1961 November 28 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
    - 314. Reply to "Making the Punishment Fit the Crime" by Franklin Zimring, The Hastings Center Report, 1977 August (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
    - 315. "Thomas Szasz and the Myth of Mental Illness", The American Spectator, 1978 February (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
    - 316. "The Growth of the Imperial Judiciary", Policy Review, 1978 Spring (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
    - 317. "The Collapse of the Case Against Capital Punishment", National Review, 1978 March 31 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
    - 318. "Yoo-hoo! Yooganda?" Review of "Just and Unjust Wars" by Michael Walzer, National Review, 1978 April 14 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
    - 319. Letter to the Editor on Hadley Arkes and Natural Law, The American Spectator, 1978 June-1978 July (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
    - 320. Religion and the Intellectuals, The New American Review, 1978 April-1978 May (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
    - 321. "Liberty: Negative or Positive", Harvard Journal of Law and Public Policy, 1978 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
    - 322. "Behind the Violence", Interview, U.S. News and World Report, 1978 December 11 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
    - 323. "A Response to Bedau", Arizona State Law Journal, Vol. 4, 1977 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
    - 324. "Beliefs and Verbal Vehemence", Review of "The Psychological Society" by Martin L. Goss and "The Myth of Psychotherapy" by Thomas Szasz, Chronicles of Culture, 1978 November-1978 December (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
    - 325. "Gay Advocates", Letter to the Editor on Homosexual Teachers, National Review, 1978 November 24 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
    - 328. Comment on Vernon Fox's Review of Punishing Criminals", American Journal of Sociology, 1979 January (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
    - 329. "Mont Pelerin Strikes Again", National Review, 1979 February 16 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
    - 330. "Crime or Punishment?" National Review, 1979 March 02 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
    - 332. "Labor Unions in a Free Market", Imprimus, 1979 March (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
    - 333. "Punishing Victims", Review of "The Crime Victim's Book" by Bard and Sangrey, and "Victims" by J.L. Barkas, Saturday Review, 1979 March 17 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 41)
    - 334. "Notes on Foreign Policy, Armies, and Money", Policy Review, 1979 Spring (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 42)
    - 335. "A Tale of Three Cities", National Review, 1979 April 27 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 43)
    - 336. "Punitive Sentences", Hofstra Law Review, 1978 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 44)
    - 337. "Libertarians and Conservatives", National Review, 1979 June 08 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 45)
    - 338. "Has the Libertarian Movement Gone Kooky?" National Review, 1979 August 03 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 46)
    - 339. "A Dialogue", With Ronald Dworkin on Legal Rights and Moral Wrongs, The American Spectator, 1979 June-1979 July (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 47)
    - 340. Reviews of "Capitalism: Sources of Hostility", Heritage Foundation, 1979 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 48)
    - 340a. "Marktfeindlichkeit, Warum?" (German), Reviews, Philosophia Verlag, 1983 January 19 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 49)
    - 340a. Review of "Justice and Punishment" edited by J.B. Cederblom and William L. Blizek, The American Political Science Review, 1979 March (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 50)
    - 341. "Does Society Have A Legitimate Interest In A Political Leader's Sex Life?" Medical Aspects of Human Sexuality, 1979 October (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 51)
    - 342. "Should the Government Subsidize the Arts?" Policy Review, 1979 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 52)
    - 343. "Trial Balloons", Taxing and Spending, 1979 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 53)
    - 344. "Trying to See the Distant Future", Review of "World Economic Development: 1979 and beyond" by Herman Kahn, Fortune, 1979 October 08 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 54)
    - 345. "Unpardonable Pardon", (Patty Hearst), Equitas, 1979 March (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 55)
    - 346. "Dealing with the Death Penalty", Letter to the Editor, Sunday New York Times Magazine, 1979 May 06 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 56)
    - 347. "Breaking Bones", Review of "Breaking Ranks" by Norman Podhoretz, National Review, 1980 February 08 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 57)
    - 348. "Birds, Bees, and Bathroom Tours", (Sex Education Revisited), National Review, 1979 December 07 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 58)
    - 349. "Realistic Steps for Reforming Welfare", Journal of the Institute for Socioeconomic Studies, 1979 Winter (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 59)
    - 350. "Psychoanalyzing Jimmy Carter", Review of "Jimmy Carter: An Interpretive Biography" by B. Mazlish, Fortune, 1980 April 02 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 60)
    - 351. "Prisons Cost Too Much Because They are Too Secure", Corrections, 1980 April (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 61)
    - 352. "Pornography and Censorship", Policy Review, 1980 Summer (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 62)
    - 353. "A Good Man Gone Wrong", Review of "The Zero Sum Society" by Lester Thurow, National Review, 1980 November 28 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 63)
    - 354. Review of "For Capital Punishment" by Walter Berns, American Political Science Review, 1980 June (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 64)
    - 355. "What Textbooks Say About Criminality", University Bookman, 1980 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 65)
    - 356. "Once More Without Feeling", Review of "Thy Neighbor's Wife" by Guy Talese, National Review, 1981 March 06 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 66)
    - 357. Letter to the Editor on Midge Decter's "The Boys on the Beach (Homosexuality)", Commentary, 1980 December (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 67)
    - 358. "Judgement and Delinquency", Letter to the Editor on "What Works?" by Robert Wilson, Character, 1981 February (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 68)
    - 359. "Alliance with China", Letter to the Editor on "China Policy for the 1980s", by Michael Oksenberg, Foreign Affairs, 1981 Spring (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 69)
    - 360. "In Response to Isaac Rosenfeld", Letter to the Editor, Partisan Review, No.3, 1980 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 70)
    - 361. Letter to the Editor on "Peers" by David W. Johnson, Character, 1981 November (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 71)
    - 362. Letter to the Editor on "The Ministry of Culture" by Michael M. Mooney, Harper's, Undated (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 72)
    - 363. "Marxism as Pseudo-Science", Unification Theological Seminary, Barrytown, NY, and Reason Papers, No.12, 1980 October 11; 1987 Spring (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 73)
    - 364. Lengthy Quotes in "The Critique of Mental Illness" by William Hasker, Journal of Psychology and Theology, 1977 Spring (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 74)
    - 365. Letter to the Editor on "The Future Danger" by Norman Podhoretz, Commentary, 1981 August (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 75)
    - 366. "An American Foreign Legion?" Policy Review, 1981 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 76)
    - 367. "Can Philosophers Be Angry?" Letter to the Editor on Sonya Rudikoff's Essay of the Same Title, The American Scholar, 1981 Winter-1982 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 77)
    - 368. "The Case for Suppressing Pornography", The Washington Star, 1980 May 28 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 78)
    - 369. Testimony on Gun Control before the Joint Assembly Senate Committee Hearing, 1980 April 16 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 79)
    - 370. "Neutrality Won't Work for Europe", Letter to the Editor on "Finlandization", Editorial by Irving Kristol, Wall Street Journal, 1981 August 05 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 80)
    - 371. Letter to the Editor on "The Portland Declaration" by Kudhnelt-Leddihn, National Review, 1981 November 13 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 81)
    - 372. Review of "The Letters of Karl Marx" by Saul Padover, Hadassah Magazine, 1980 June-1980 July (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 82)
    - 373. "Punishment as a Device for Controlling the Crime Rate", Rutgers Law Review, 1981 Spring (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 83)
    - 374. "Sense and Nonsense About Wealth and Poverty", Review of "Wealth and Poverty" by George Gilder, Fortune, 1981 July 13 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 84)
    - 375. "Bedpan Hospitality", The American Spectator, 1981 December (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 85)
    - 376. Testimony on the Selection and Confirmation of Federal Judges before the Committee on the Judiciary: U.S. Senate (Mikua), 1979 July 19 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 86)
    - 377. "The President Governs Well", (Carter), Sunday New York Times, 1979 January 28 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 87)
    - 378. "How to Make Hospitals Hospitable", Fortune, 1982 May 17 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 88)
    - 379. "Gildering the Lily", Review of "Capitalism Is For Givers" by George Gilder, The American Spectator, 1982 May (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 89)
    - 380. "Making Crime Cost and Lawfulness Pay", Society, 1982 July-1982 August (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 90)
    - 381. "The Criminal Law as a Threat System", Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1982 Summer (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 91)
    - 381a. "Reply To Dr. John Braithwaite", Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1982 Summer (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 92)
    - 382. "Comment on Challenging Just Deserts" by John Braithwaite, Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1982 Summer (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 93)
    - 383. "Feeble Attack on Tuition Tax Credits", New York Times, 1982 September 11 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 94)
    - 384. "Fear of Punishment", (John Hinkley), The Advocate, Fordham Univ. Law School, 1982 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 95)
    - 385. Letter to the Editor on "The Bible's Inspired Art" by Chaim Potk, New York Times Sunday Magazine, 1982 November 14 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 96)
    - 386. Letter to the Editor on "Is Homosexuality Normal?" by Steven Goldberg, Policy Review, 1983 Winter (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 97)
    - 387. "Natural Law and Natural Rights", in "Sidney Hook; Philosopher of Democracy and Humanism", edited by Paul Kurtz, Prometheus Books, and Policy Review, 1983 Winter; 1983 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 98)
    - 388. "U.S. Taxpayers Carrying Burden to Protect Allies", The Pittsburgh Press, 1982 December 18 (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 99)
    - 389. "Could Successful Rehabilitation Reduce the Crime Rate?" Journal Of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1982 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 100)
    - 389a. "How Not To Cut Crime - Rehabilitating Criminals Cannot Cut Crime", Policy Review, 1983 Fall (Box 4 (2-Publications), Folder 101)
    - 390. "When Aiding Latins", (Aid to Central America), New York Times, 1983 February 03 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
    - 391. Letter to the Editor on "Dressing Down" by Michael Kinsley, Harpers, 1983 April (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
    - 392. "Strange news from the South Seas", Review of "Margaret mead and Samoa" by Derek Freeman, Fortune, 1983 April 18 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
    - 393. "Bedpan Hospitality II", The American Spectator, 1983 May (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
    - 394. "How to Get a handle on the Addiction Problem", Review of "The Hardest Drug" by John Kaplin, Wall Street Journal, 1983 May 10 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
    - 395. "Should We Bring Home the Troops?" National Review, 1983 June 24 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
    - 396. "The Great Government Should Stay Away", Journal of Arts, Management and Law, 1983 Spring (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
    - 397. Poem on Dinesh D'Souza's Article on Art Subsidized by Taxpayers, Policy Review, 1983 Summer (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
    - 398. "Parole harms Society and Criminals Both", Los Angeles Times, 1983 May 26 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
    - 399. "Capital Punishment", Debate Transcript Between E.v.d. Haag and Henry Schwarzschild, from "The American Debate", Washington, D.C., and ABA Journal, 1983 July 24; 1985 April (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
    - 400. Review of "The Homosexual Network" by Enrique T. Rueda, The American Spectator, 1983 September (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
    - 401. "The Media and Revolution", Lecture Given at the World Media Conference, Cartagena, Columbia, 1983 September 04-1983 September 10 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
    - 402. "For the Death Penalty", New York Times, Op. Ed, 1983 October 17 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
    - 403. Review of "Making America Work Again" by J. Morton Davis, National Review, 1983 December 09 (Box 5 (2-Publications), Folder 14)